All right.
Our last presenter for this panel
is Katarina
Srebotnik from Nagoya University.
When AI magic meets creative writing, the
AI Nobody's Story
literary prize and the boundaries
of non-human co-authorship.
Take it away.
Hey. So
I hope you can see it.
My name is
and I'm currently doing my
ethnography.
Today I'm going to be presenting
on the coming.
Example
of how some mechanisms of consecration and
writers are adapted in the context of AI,
and my particular example
stems from the Japanese
literal in context.
First important,
I would like to start with
explaining the magic in my title.
So what I'm relying on here
are the different emergency areas
of magical metaphors of generative
AI that are situated
within the broader
critique of technological imaginaries.
And to give just one example, recently
in Japan, like I'm sure
in many other contexts, there has been
this emerging trend of thinking
about how to live together with AI,
which sometimes resulted in publication
of some books
that argue
that it's important to befriend AI,
or to use it as some kind of companion
rather than a tool.
One example is, for instance,
the associate
on friendships with,
I believe, AI neutral,
but there are many of those,
and besides that,
there are also very
old tradition of
different so-called
useless robots being developed
that are mostly just cute
and don't really do anything
that is, for instance,
Roboto or love it.
Combining words for love and Robert.
And what all of these examples
demonstrate is technologies
as companion humans
need to coexist
with rather than cytokines or argue with.
And here it's possible to see friendliness
and acceptance as a way to counter
technological anxieties.
But at the same time, while
this view sounds a little bit utopian,
it actually also creates
some very interesting implications
for literary studies and the concept
of authorship in particular.
So in today's presentation,
I'm going to focus
on this photography of magic
as a way of promoting creative writing.
And I'm also going to look
at the blurriness of boundaries
between the literally author
and the tool development. And
also I'm going to, once again,
the power
imbalance and collective authorship.
So my main can study is AI.
Nobody still or also a novelist,
which is a tool that is based on a corpus
of approximately 500 data bites or
quite a lot of different books.
So I know that is is positioned as AI
as Japan's largest public
Japanese novel assistant tool, and.
Mainly built upon bunko,
which is a resource that digitize
Japanese books with expired copyright.
But while it does specify
the source,
it also relies on some unspecified data
from novels and paperbacks,
which are never really elaborated on.
And the way that it works is that it
mainly builds upon three different modes.
There is the assistant mode
and then the story mode and the chat mode.
So there is a lot of interaction happening
during the process of writing,
and it's also gradually
being adapted into English.
So there is a possibility that it will
eventually try
to go into a more multilingual direction.
But what it's already trying to do
is to position itself
in a very specific way.
For instance, in this quote
by one of the
main developers, they talk about how
processes advanced lexical database
made available thanks to the affordances
of the web, and supports the unique
creative practices of its user stand.
The developer describes
it as being neither a god
nor a slave,
but as a ginger bell or a theory.
While the development process
is still ongoing, we hope that
the amount of information available
on the internet continues to grow.
It will turn into a cherished theory
companion for writers.
So what is interested
in this form of advertisement
is that not only does it
rely on different binaries
so I can be either a slave
or a godlike entity,
but it also presents the database itself
as a building out of nowhere
and kind of just existing and carrying
no specific implications.
And it also shifts from users to writers,
showing that everyone can be a writer
if only they use the tool.
Moreover, there is also an association
with AI is something
that is made to be domesticated, and
the use of AI in self is also presented
as both increasing
but also a little bit inevitable.
And one of the other way
that I know is to promote
their tool is organizing
their very own little context.
And nobody's surprise,
this context is only exception texts
that are written
with the assistance of AI,
and it opens, whether irregularly.
So far there has been tutors
first and 2022 and then another in 2025.
And what's interesting is the way
that it mimics the conventions of other,
literally prizes.
For instance, it invites judges
active in the literary world.
It also publishes the winning Texas
physical books.
So it seems rather dependent
on print based media.
And none of the texts
are really available online.
But the information about them is so
most of
the and
the winners also submits their text
and the band names, which I'm
going to return to a little bit later.
And the connectivity of authorship
is evident not only in the way
how the users are encouraged
to coauthor with the tool,
but also in
in the way that the collection of stories
that they published
are always marked as coauthored.
So it's possible
to see how the author here
emerges as a collective,
or maybe even distributed construct
that heavily relies on the symbiosis
with a particular tune,
and the two at times is also emphasized
a bit more than those actually using it.
So the authors invisibility here is also
curiously juxtaposed
against the developers visibility,
which becomes even more evident
on the example
of some of the interviews that star
or the main developer of the tool gives.
So there is already a very
prominent growing term.
A trend of
seeing AI is something that is meant
to help the writers
to channel their creativity,
without actually necessarily
only engaging in writing.
For instance,
who is another writer using AI?
And his text
very prominently argues that in a sense,
using AI systems means turning
right writers into movie producers.
Producers choose the direction, but it is
actors and stylists
who do the actual work.
A lot of people are involved
in the process, but the final product
is still advertised
as being produced by someone, right?
And another example of this
in the context of barista,
is how it blurs the boundaries
between the two and the author,
while still reinforcing the image
of a single creator in charge.
But in this case,
the creator is the developer of the tool,
or in particular, stop,
who started developing it
as a passion project,
but gradually expanded it later on to
to make it something for profit.
So star himself becomes the spokesperson
of the context, and the other writers
and authors
are never actually interviewed,
never even appear in public.
So he always becomes the face
of the context,
and the participants at the same time
are not really allowed
this much visibility and mainly remain
the users
or perhaps producers of the tool.
So the context is reporting
be seen as selectively anonymous,
not in the sense that the actual writers
don't appear, but in the sense
that they always stay on the background
of the tool that they use.
And in particular,
the connection
between the nicknames turning into pen
name is seem to be an interesting trend
that is not only available,
evident on the example of AI Bristol,
but is also a scene
and some other examples.
For instance, for stellata,
the first Japanese literary journal
that focuses on I didn't entries.
Many, if not most, of the writers
are writing under pen names, and
in the
emerging All About Generative
AI exhibition,
most of the creators also use their pen
names further than the real names.
So to conclude, it is possible
to see how I know there is the highlights
the collectivity of authorship,
but it also shows how it involves
a certain power imbalance,
and the writers in this case can be seen
almost auxiliary to the tool
appearing as before,
only promoted, and the figure of
the author is an originator of
the text gets replaced here
with that of the developer as an original,
then originator of the two.
So thank you for your attention
and it's all for me today.